#### ADRIAN IKE BARRANCO

Taylorsville, UT, 84129

Phone: 385-229-7480 | Email: <u>barranco.ike@gmail.com</u>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ike-barranco/ | GitHub: https://github.com/ikemous | Portfolio:

https://ikemous.herokuapp.com/

### **SUMMARY**

IT specialist with an active Secret Clearance and CompTIA Security+ Certificate. I have over three years of experience in System Administration, Network Administration, CNOC Monitoring, troubleshooting and various coding languages. Trained to and deployed Cisco devices while deployed with the Utah Army National Guard. While in college I've completed multiple classes in programming which included HTML, CSS, C#, C++, and SEO. I've also completed Trilogies Coding Bootcamp hosted by the University of Utah. Technologies covered by this course are: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, APIs, MySQL, Handlebars, Node, Express, MongoDB, and React.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: HTML, CSS, APIs, Node.js, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL, Sequelize, MongoDB, Mongoose, Handlebars, React.js

Applications: Git, Visual Studio Code, MySQL Workbench, MongoDB Compass, Robo3T

#### **PROJECTS**

**Reactications** [https://github.com/ikemous/react-applications] https://master.dm4of32gdirop.amplifyapp.com/

- Website with 3 mini projects using several technologies
- Front End Developer
- Technologies: React, Typescript, AWS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

**HALP** | https://github.com/Lancasting/Final-Project | https://halp-me.herokuapp.com/

- Website ticketing system with a NOSQL database
- Full-Stack Developer, tasks assigned through GitHub projects
- Technologies: React, Node, MongoDB, CSS, HTML, CSS, Semantic

**Aninder** | https://github.com/ikemous/React-Cat-Or-Dog | https://aninder.herokuapp.com/

- Website to find your new friend and saving them with a NOSQL database
- Full stack developer
- Technologies: React, Node, MongoDB, CSS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

Movie Lover | https://github.com/Robbie2497/Project-2 | https://projectdash.herokuapp.com/

- Website to search movies by name and then save them to view later using an SQL database
- Responsibilities were assigned through project cards in GitHub
- Technologies: JavaScript, jQuery, API, Node, Express, Handlebars, Sequelize, CSS, HTML, MYSQL

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Network Operation Center Monitor 2020 – Current Conduent Sandv. UT

- Verify issues are occurring using SolarWinds, Netcool and LiveNX
- Use networking devices to troubleshoot and find more information on downed items
- Use ServiceNow to create/track issues
- Communicate with various Internet Service Providers for connection verification.

- Create tickets using Internet Service Provider ticketing systems
- Actively communicate with multiple IT departments
- Conduent CNOC SharePoint Committee member

# Information Technology Specialist 2018 – Current Utah Army National Guard Camp Williams, UT

- Troubleshoot software and hardware
- Use active directory to create/delete/update users
- Assist in deploying Windows Servers
- Configure and maintain Cisco routers and switches
- Troubleshoot Network issues using Cisco and Satellite devices
- Document and maintain network flow diagrams
- Create detailed shift notes on issues/resolutions occurred during shifts
- Use section made or Remedy Ticketing Systems to create/track issues
- Configure General Dynamic TACLANES and fill with encryption
- Create/updated Cisco Call Manager Routes and phones
- Network/System administrator for several locations
- Helpdesk services for over 100 soldiers supporting multiple locations

## Help Desk Technician L1 2019 – 2020

TEKsystems Sandy, UT

- Customer service call center helpdesk technician
- Use ServiceNow ticketing system to create tickets
- Remotely troubleshoot software/hardware issues

## **RSP Administration Specialist** 2015 – 2018

Utah Army National Guard Camp Williams, UT

- Initiate helpdesk tickets for end user accounts and issues with Remedy Ticketing System
- Troubleshoot and route network printers for end users
- Troubleshoot and install applications for end users
- Initial entry training career advisor
- Use Army Pay Management System to issue pay or fix pay issues
- Check numerous documents to ensure 100% accuracy with the soldier's information
- Create/instruct training for initial entry training soldiers
- Obtained expert drivers' badge for being lead vehicle operator for transportation of soldiers and office/training equipment

### **EDUCATION**

Trilogy Coding Bootcamp, Certification: University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT (2020-2020)

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Computer Science w/ Emphasis in Programming, Bachelors: American Public University, Charles Town WV (2018-2022)

72/120 Credits Complete

**COMPTIA Security+, Certificate:** Salt Lake City, UT (2019)

Professional IT Certification - https://www.comptia.org/certifications/security

Information Technology Specialist(25B), Certification: Army, Camp Williams UT (2018-2018)

Computer Science, Bachelors: Utah Valley University, Provo UT (2017-2018)

**General Education:** Salt Lake Community College, Salt Lake City UT (2016-2017)